This video is brought to you by
Squarespace, an all-in-one platform for
building a brand and growing your
business online. Hello, my name is Mina
and I'm a video essay pill YouTube maxer
here to talk about the internetification
of our vocabulary.
If that didn't make any sense to you,
consider yourself lucky. Ironically,
despite the fact that we're outdoors
today, this topic is incredibly online,
which by the way, hello, new background,
new fruit. We actually grew these in our
yard. Um, but they have seeds. I'm
always trying to figure out what works
and what makes the viewing experience
more engaging and people responded well
to my backyard setup in the YouTube
short I posted some time ago. So, I
thought I'd try it out long form style.
Anyways, the topic at hand. Is it just
me or is there a new brain rotted flavor
to a lot of today's slang?
>> I'm over here or farming, cooking,
sweating, full sigma, borderline giga
chatting.
>> Nowadays, everyone is attaching suffixes
like maxing, pled, and mog to just about
any word. And the frame before you
leave.
>> Frame mom.
>> Stay positive. Yeah. Positive maxing.
>> I would say I'm pretty IQ pilled.
>> IQ pill.
>> Drinking lots of coffee today. You're
coffee maxing.
>> Damn. Fine. Cup of coffee.
>> Obsessed with Matt Damon because of the
Odyssey press tour. You're Damon Pilled.
To break it down for you real quick, max
is shorthand for maximizing a behavior
or action. Pilled means to be convinced
into a lifestyle. It takes from the
Matrix. And mog means to look or perform
better than someone else. I am not a
betting woman, but if I were, and no,
this is not going to lead into a poly
market sponsorship. I'm realizing how
that sentence just sounded. I'd bet that
not everyone using these terms knows
that they actually originated in incel
forums. For anyone who needs a refresher
on what an incel is, the original online
incel community was founded in 1997 by a
Canadian university student named Alana,
who is looking to connect with people of
all genders to discuss feelings of
loneliness and struggles with dating.
Alana's website and mailing list were
called Alana's Involuntary Celibacy
Project and she describes the early site
as a generally supportive
non-discriminatory place. She eventually
abbreviated involuntary celibacy to
imbecile and it was later further
abbreviated by someone else to incel as
it was just easier to say. In the
decades since Alana founded her website,
the Incel community has taken on a new
life, getting colonized by a group of
aggressive, misogynistic men who believe
they're unable to find romantic partners
due to fixed genetic traits and women
being overly autonomous in society. In
his book, Algo Speak, linguist Adamic
explains that as the online incel
community took a darker turn, shared
language and slang became an important
way for members to signal in-group
identity. Showcasing your proficiency in
incel terms showed that you had a deep
understanding of pseudoscientific incel
ideology, allowing you to get closer to
true cell status or the most respected
inner circle of incels. This terminology
stayed within the community for quite a
while until it started getting exported
out of incel circles via memes. Adam
explains that incels began intentionally
spreading their rhetoric in subreddits
adjacent to r/insel. This included
subreddits related to applying to
college where Incels knew they would
likely reach impressionable
inexperienced teenage boys as well as
r/RateMe where people asked for feedback
on their physical appearances. On these
subreddits, incelss could disguise looks
maxing language as helpful suggestions,
evaluating people based on their
interocular distance, canal tilt, and
hunter eyes, and encouraging them to
improve their facial structure through
mewing, a tongue exercise so that they
could mog others. If people were
interested in exploring what these terms
meant further, r/insel was just a hop,
skip, and a jump away. According to
Adam, memes making fun of incelss began
popping up on Instagram and Twitter in
2021, later going even more viral on
reals and Tik Tok. As these terms moved
further away from their source, they
soon became decontextualized from their
original meanings. People started using
incel slang not to signal their incel
identity, but to make fun of incels
using irony. On teaching subreddits,
there are teachers debating whether or
not the young boys in their classroom
are sincerely using incel language or
just using it as a joke. with one user
saying, "I found it hard to tell which
boys are buying in and which boys are
paring it because they find it
ridiculous." But of course, there were
still people using the term sincerely,
likely not understanding their
misogynistic roots. For example, Adam
writes that many beauty influencers
began unknowingly using looks maxing
terms on Tik Tok, demonstrating how to
use canthal tilt to put on eyeliner or
posting video filters rating themselves
on metrics like forehead size and
interocular distance. I remember ending
up on the site of Tik Tok years ago and
being horrified that we were essentially
tapping back into phronology, a field of
pseudocience that rose to prominence in
the Victorian era to justify um
eugenics. Phronology essentially ranks
certain features like skull shape into
good versus evil categories, less we
forget the viral angel versus witch
skull. It's so obviously ridiculous and
racist because certain ethnic groups
have certain features and that has
nothing to do with their sense of
morality, obviously. but it was getting
repackaged in this seemingly harmless
way of self-catgorization akid to like
myer Briggs or astrological signs.
>> So, this person is not just a pretty
face, she's going to be a good writer
and a great conversationalist as well.
>> Squarespace is a fantastic platform to
help you build the website of your
dreams for both desktop and mobile
optimization. They have tons of pre-made
templates and extra customization
options so that you can make your
website uniquely you. A lot of people
make websites because they want to open
their own storefronts, and Squarespace
makes the process super easy. You can
sell anything from physical products to
memberships to consultation services. If
what you're trying to sell is service
based and requires appointment booking,
Squarespace makes it super easy by
offering the scheduling feature so that
any clients can book a time with you
with just a click of a few buttons. They
also have a built-in email campaign
feature. If you want to connect more
with your clients, you can start with
just any email template. And of course,
you have analytics to track your
campaign impact as well. Check out
squarespace.com for a free trial. And
when you're ready to launch, go to
squarespace.com/me
to get 10% off your first purchase of a
website or domain. Regardless of why
someone uses this language naively,
insily, or ironically, this language has
permeated so much all over the internet
that it's nearly impossible to avoid it,
even from brand accounts. The magazine
Days recently posted a series of reels
asking celebrities at Paris Fashion Week
what they're maxing. And Duolingo has
posted videos of their mascot mewing and
has joked about making a brain rock
course to teach people terms like Sigma.
>> Um, what a sigma.
>> Personal anecdote time. And I'm
technically at fault here, but Daz
interviewed me for a short form segment
several months ago and I was talking on
the fly because, you know, it's a video
interview and I said that I was human
maxing. Okay, so that gets posted. It
gets a decent amount of engagement and
then a brand comes into my inbox asking
me to make a short form video for their
product through the lens of human maxing
and in their brief they attached my
dazed interview. After reading that I
was like oh my god we cannot be serious
right now. Like I'm cringing at this
interview moment. And meanwhile brand
reps are unironically sliding and saying
wow trend alert trendy buzzword alert.
Let's go deeper with that. But to their
credit, studies do show that brands that
incorporate internet slang and
advertising significantly increase
audience attention. At the same time,
doesn't necessarily improve product
evaluation or brand awareness. In fact,
researchers found that an excessive use
of internet slang may cause the audience
to feel frivolous, which damages the
trust that consumers have in a brand or
product. This study was published in
2019, though, and a lot has changed
since then. The pandemic may have
rutdded our brains to the point where we
find it to be totally normal for the
Wendy's Twitter account to just start
posting about mogging Ronald McDonald.
In all seriousness, I do think it's so
dystopian that whenever brands jump into
a comment thread, normal people will
reply to those comments as if they're
written by their friends. It just like
anthropomorphicizes these brands. Kate
Lindsay wrote an awesome essay about it
for her Substack Embedded in which she
shared an example Blue Sky post. Parker
Malloy posted, "Thads is fascinating.
Truly, there are thousands of people
raging about this girl boss/w wild child
post from Pepsi." The post in question,
Pepsi's brand social manager wrote,
"Pepsi's Wild Cherry is what happens
when Regular Cherry stops asking for
permission." Lindsay concludes, "I need
you to stop celebrating brands for
posting inane slop, but also to stop
getting mad at them for anything other
than failing to deliver their product.
You should only be tweeting angrily at
Pepsi if you bought a bottle and there
was a screw in it. Anything more comes
dangerously close to granting brands
personhood, which will only further
contribute to the way our culture,
economy, and politics put their
interests above our own. Because for
some reason, so do we. But why exactly
are brands using these terms? Well, it's
because we are using these terms. So why
are we using these terms? One
explanation is that the suffix format of
many of these terms enhances their
mumatic qualities. It's easy to simply
tack on maxed or pled or even non-insol
related suffixes like ification or
isation onto an existing word and create
a new term joining in on the fun of a
shared cultural trend. Just think about
all the aesthetic cores the internet has
coined and how many times usie was added
onto random nouns in the late 2010s. As
Gretcha McCullik writes in her book
because internet, we pick up on patterns
in internet language without necessarily
thinking about it. In her book, she
explains that even the seemingly
spontaneous, nonsensical key smash
lapping expression has a pattern to it,
almost always beginning with an A or
ASDF and commonly including letters and
icons on the home row of the keyboard.
Users will sometimes even backspace and
re smash their key smash to make sure it
adheres to this standardized format.
Language is to communicate and to be a
part of something. Also, incel slang has
a pessimistic outlook to it that
parallels Jenz's doomspeak, a term
Amanda Montel coined in her book, The
Age of Magical Overthinking, to describe
dystopian or detached jargon used by
young people, including terms like
dissociating, doomscrolling, bedrotting,
and the ever famous it's over memes.
Incels actually coined the phrase LD AR
or lay down and rot before bed rotting
even became a popular term. I've asked
around about this and generally people
seem to be pretty divided on whether
incel terms spilling into mainstream
culture is good or bad for the incel
cause. And I kind of see both sides. On
one hand, as these terms become more
mainstream, they become more
decontextualized from incel communities,
which may rob incels of their power as
they no longer have shared lingo to tie
them together until, of course, they
create new terminology. And trust me,
they will and they already do. There's
hundreds of other terms that have yet to
hit the mainstream. I actually um
unfortunately learned what wage cuck was
the other day, aka a derogatory term,
obviously. Um meaning a person who works
a mindless, slowpaying job. And
congrats, now you've learned it, too. On
the other hand, I completely understand
why some people worry that these terms
may inadvertently indoctrinate people
into incel communities. For example, if
middle school boys with smartphones
begin engaging with Tik Toks using incel
terms that they find funny, they may
also start getting served actual incel
content using those terms, leading them
into a darker and more dangerous
algorithm. In Algo Speak, Adam
references an old adage of internet
culture known as PO law, which suggests
that any sarcastic expression of extreme
views can be mistaken for a sincere
expression of those views and vice
versa. I feel like because I'm a woman
in my late 20s, um I don't interact with
a lot of incelss, but they are scary. I
was actually out with a friend in
Silverlake for a dinner and we were
waiting for a table outside this
restaurant because there was not no
space to wait inside the restaurant, but
it was fine and and it was fine until
this guy came over to talk to us and it
actually just felt like a hostage
situation. Like he kept asking us about
what we thought about his appearance. He
asked us about looks maxing um and if he
needed it and then he told us he was gay
but he wanted to look straight and he
was like if I'm walking with a woman I
want other people to think that I could
have hit her. It was just like crazy
stuff. I mean I don't know what happened
in his life to get him to this point.
But I can imagine that any of these guys
like him who were like in this looks
maxing wormhole started out as little
boys who were just playing around on the
internet. People ask me to put them on.
Put me on, bro.
>> If you want a submissive traditional
female, you need to be the dominant
assertive male and you adhere to your
duties.
>> Braden Peters, better known as
Clvicular, is the world leading looks
maxer.
>> I began blowing up on social media and I
wanted to ascend in a very short time
frame. So, I was math maxing to lean out
as much as possible. [music]
>> Since there is no God, maxing doesn't
stop with just looks. It now applies to
everything.
>> You need to be silly goose maxing.
>> Welcome back to episode two of yogurt
maxing.
>> This is the sign from your universe to
start read maxing and intellectual
maxing.
>> What is the new word ansole? What is the
word?
>> Insoul. It's um involuntary celibate.
>> Easing into it. How has the manosphere
infiltrated mainstream culture? How do
you think it became as big as it is
today? I would say that the manosphere
originated in kind of more like shadowy
online territory in the early 2000s and
it dates back to pickup artistry which
first emerged even in a pre-in context
uh but started to pick up traction
especially among young men with the goal
of meeting and getting in relationships
with women through these manipulation
tactics. So that's kind of like the
foundation of a lot of what we think of
as the manosphere today. And even if you
look at some of the biggest manosphere
icons like Andrew Tate, they are
basically doing the same thing. They've
just made it even more industrial, I
would say. Like the operation has scaled
up. They're not just using these tactics
to pick up women. They're also building
these like exploitative networks and
businesses built around exploiting
women. So they use social media to grow
and spread that message. And what's
insidious about it is I think a lot of
times when it's divorced from the full
context, people don't even necessarily
know that what they're looking at is the
manosphere. They also like use pop
culture and trending topics to sort of
breed these ideologies. The Debt vurd
trial is a big example of this where a
lot of the language around that case was
manosphere ideology and people don't
even know that they just are viewing it
as like mindless pop culture
entertainment.
>> For the people who are using the
language like in a I guess like ironic
or combative way, do you think that
actually works as any kind of political
movement?
>> It doesn't have to be insidious and it
also doesn't have to be public facing.
Like if you're joking around with your
friends and you're a group chat, like I
don't think you're necessarily harming
anyone. But I think that unfortunately
like things on the internet posts lack
context a lot of the time. So if you're
making a viral post where you're like
trying to dunk on a right-winger by
using this language, most of the people
seeing that post probably have no idea
what you're actually doing. And the
danger in that is that just the more
viral traction that these terms get, the
more it becomes a rabbit hole and the
more that it normalizes this language in
general. Cuz I think a lot of people
when they put things out there, they
just kind of assume that like, well, I
know what I'm doing, so I assume
everyone else knows what I'm doing. But
we know that that's not the case. Um,
and I just think that as the language
becomes more commonly used and embraced,
like I think back to those kids in
classrooms and I'm like, well, now that
you have all of these like second
graders like using this terminology when
they encounter manosphere influencers on
their feeds, which they will, like these
algorithms, they're being fed directly
into them. Now, they're not having red
flags or alarm bells go off because the
language has been normalized.
>> Longer a dog whistle.
>> Exactly. Exactly. And that's the thing
that I worry about the most is that
young people don't necessarily have like
the tools or the education or the skills
to assess this material critically,
which I think makes them more vulnerable
to these pipelines that are literally
built to like trap them. Let's shift
gears a bit and talk about how new words
are created in general.
As we've learned from incel slang, we
can create new words by adding prefixes
or suffixes to existing ones, which is
formerly known as derivation. We can
also create words through back
formation, which involves removing
prefixes and suffixes. This is how we
created the word sleas out of sleazy in
1967. We can also compound words
together, borrow words from other
languages, create words by imitating
sounds, and even create new words out of
misspellings or misprononunciations. But
existing words can also shift in meaning
through a context collapse which occurs
when a word moves to a new domain and
gains a different meaning within this
new context as is occurring with the
incel terms in mainstream language.
Writer Tiffany Ing also explains that
secondary meanings for words can become
the dominant definition after being
adopted in new contexts, a process she
refers to as resemanticization.
Ing illustrates this concept by
explaining how the word whimsy is
shifting meaning. The dictionary
definition of whimsy is an unusual,
unexpected or fancful idea, a whim.
However, online, whimsy is starting to
mean anything colorful or juvenile. This
is a slight shift from its original
definition. But this has been happening
long before the internet. Take the word
villain, which was previously used to
refer to a peasant farmer. That was
something I learned. But after being
sused with the values of the snobby
aristocracy, over time it shifted in
meaning to describe someone who was not
bound by the nightly coat of chivalry
and thus a bad person. In because
internet, Gretchian McCullik also
demonstrates how words and phrases can
gain new life in new contexts by
analyzing the term lol. First, LOL was
coined to describe a specific function,
laugh out loud. but after being used in
different contexts ironically is come to
signify an expression of nonchalance
when it's lowercase and I don't know why
I said like that and placed after a
statement such as in the phrase I'm so
tired lol particularly among zennials
this secondary meaning has become the
dominant definition if you see an all
caps lol used to actually denote
laughing out loud these days you'd
probably assume it's a boomer of this is
to say that language is constantly
changing as culture changes is every
year we create about 5,400 new English
words and roughly a thousand of those
are added to the English dictionary.
Some of them are more publicized such as
the case of the word selfie which Oxford
dictionaries added in August 2013 later
dubbing it word of the year. But some of
them are words that we already thought
were in the dictionary but were
belatedly formalized such as the case
with crime rate which the Oxford English
dictionary published as being a new word
added in March 2025. And some words are
getting new definitions like we talked
about, such as the word drill, which now
has 10 definitions. The last one added
in 2025 referring to drill as a genre of
music. And then some words are just
words I've never heard of before, like
vagring, which was also added in early
2025, even though Oxford English
dictionary considered the word obsolete
with evidence of it being used mostly in
the 1600s. Why did it take so long to
finally get added? Linguists, please let
me know. I'm so curious. Bottom line is
that linguistic changes such as the
emergence of new slang and words
shifting in meaning are our way of
adapting language to better fit the
state of our culture.
>> A lot of these words are like suffixes
that get and why do you think that is?
>> Language is our way of categorizing
reality. When reality shifts, we like
having new ways to label that. I think
there are influencers who capitalize on
the fact that we want more labels for
things who engage in like trend bait by
trying to come up with the new term to
pinpoint a phenomenon. I'm totally
guilty of this too. Um but we it is our
kind of like thing where we try to find
this latent cultural trend, put a pin on
it, and then people are like, "Oh, that
feels so right. That perfectly labels
what I was thinking about." And now you
turn it into an internet trend. Words
come out of countercultures, right?
there's no reason for the mainstream to
spontaneously start using a new word
because they are the status quo. So you
need to look at what groups either are
marginalized or perceive themselves as
marginalized um or are trying to do
something different and edgy. That's
where the words are coming from. And
then there's also top down words like uh
you know the word iPhone just like
>> happened because somebody called it an
iPhone and they were like a industry
leader and they introduced a product
called an iPhone. That's I guess
marketing is another source of words. I
I don't think I'm worried about you know
1984 dystopia where our language is
limited. this I I think language always
kind of risomatically expands in a new
direction and comes up with if a new
area of reality needs to be labeled we
end up labeling it and now you know
there's a market for that even so I I I
also think if you focus on the words
themselves that's like focus and and you
think that these words are culturally
deleterious that's kind of like focusing
on the symptoms of the disease rather
than the cause and if you don't like
some words that are in our vocabulary
you should ask yourself why are these
words in our vocabulary what structural
incentives exist for these words to be
brought into the mainstream and in this
case it's that social media algorithms
are incentivizing insult language to be
replicated. It's that we have created
spaces on the internet for these people
to gather. Um these things are the cause
of everything else that's going on in
culture. Um words to me are like proxies
for the underlying reality that um I'm
not concerned about the word maxing. I'm
concerned about the ideology behind the
word maxing. I think we should not be
ruthlessly optimizing everything. Um,
and that is what I'm mad about. So, I
shouldn't be upset at the word
specifically. The word is just a way to
label the greater malaise that exists.
there is sort of a homogenization or
bottleneck of how we speak that occurs
through these algorithms and through
these AI chat bots um where they say
certain stuff more or influencers
replicate certain language more and
we're on the receiving end of that and
the way we talk is just a product of the
words we see around us in the millu and
then we replicate that. So if we're
seeing a narrower band of language, it's
quite possible that language will
narrow. But through that bottleneck, I
always kind of feel like there's another
speciation event of how we're speaking
and maybe English as a whole or like you
know, language is d a language is dying
out every two weeks. I think that's the
stat. Um so that that's tragic. That's
terrible. But um also on the internet,
the way the Swifties are talking and the
K-pop fans are talking and the incels
are talking are like entirely like
languages. And there's almost like a new
birth of linguistic diversity on the
internet. And if language is just our
way to categorize reality and our
reality is changing, I don't see a
reason to be opposed to that. Um, but
there is something to be celebrated in
both the old words and the the new ones.
>> We'll go on with our history lesson.
>> So, we've talked a bit about how words
can change in meaning as they become
decontextualized over time. And we've
also talked about how many of us have
lost the origin of said words as well.
There's a lot of words that we use and
every single word has its origin story.
Every single word I just said in that
sentence has an origin story. To lighten
things up, I thought we could explore
how the English language has developed
over time. Walk with me.
It's 1066. You're a peasant farmer,
probably a surf. Despite popular belief,
life isn't that bad. Other than the
disease and infant mortality and the
lack of forks, you're clocking in only
about 27 hours of work per week. I mean,
life is pretty good. You're arranged
married to the baddest in the
village. Maybe you know how to play the
loot. And thanks to the Norman conquest
of England, you have 10,000 new French
words to use at your disposal. Yeah, you
heard me. Did you know that the Norman
conquest of England in 1066 triggered
the adoption of 10,000 French words into
the English language? Everyday words
like chair, money, and justice were all
part of this transition. The Spark's
version of what happened was that
William the Conqueror declared himself
heir to the English throne and seized it
from Harold II. Harold was actually the
last Anglo-Saxon king of England as
William, formerly the Duke of Normandy,
grew up in the Kingdom of France.
Therefore, when William took over
England, he spoke old Norman French and
the following kings of England would
also speak French until the end of the
14th century. Because he spoke French,
William began bending the verbiage
surrounding land ownership, in part
through the Domes Day Book, a
countrywide census commissioned in 1086.
The Domes day book was written in Latin,
meaning that common English people who
could only speak and read in old English
couldn't understand most of it and thus
couldn't adequately protest it. King
William actually disinherited many
English land owners of their land and
gave most of it to Norman lords. Over
time, Anglo Norman French naturally
became the language of business and law
as French aristocrats replaced the
English ruling class. As a result, many
French loan words and legal concepts
entered English law codes. In some
cases, these adoptions altered
government structures and legal
procedures. For instance, the French
introduced mayor, the old French word
for mayor, to English before the
conquest. It's questionable whether or
not the English even had a concept for
the position of mayor. Thus, King
William introduced a new word and a new
government position. Also, common modern
English legal terms like judge, jury,
parliament, advocate, defendant, verdict
all have French origin. And in his book,
The Stories of English, linguist David
Crystal writes that over time in law.
Instead of choosing between English or
French, Middle English legal ease
evolved to use both. For instance, in
the binomial breaking and entering,
breaking is of English origin and
entering is of old French origin.
Another thing I found fascinating was
that the words of Anglo-Saxon or old
English origin sound simpler and more
straightforward, reflecting the terms
used by the primarily English peasant
class, and words of Latinate origin,
largely introduced by Norman French,
sound more sophisticated and fancy,
reflecting the French aristocracy of the
1000s. The textbook example used to
exemplify this is the different words we
have for meats. For example, the
Anglo-Saxon words cow, sheep, and swine,
all used to describe livestock, came
from English-speaking farmers. But the
Latinate terms beef, mutton, and pork
used to describe food, come from the
French aristocrats who dined on these
animals. In general, Latin words tend to
be more formal, whereas Anglo-Saxon is
more familiar. It makes sense then that
most curse words are Anglo-Saxon. This
is something I actually first learned
about in a class I took from Gar
Greenwell about writing style. He talked
about how you can toggle between
Anglo-Saxon and Latinate words in your
writing depending on the level of
formality you want to convey. All in
all, David Crystal writes that the
combined influence of French and Latin
through the Norman conquest radically
altered the character of the English
language, facilitating the transition
from old English to middle English. To
put this into perspective, around the
year 1000, non-Germanic words in English
could be numbered in the hundreds. But
by 1500, the language had incorporated
tens of thousands. Crystal writes,
"Eventually, English would become the
most ethmologically multilingual
language on Earth. Today, modern English
breaks down to about 60% Latinate words,
25% Anglo-Saxon words, and the rest
being a mix of several other global
influences." Dios Mio is actually in the
Oxford English dictionary. Now, it's
really interesting that with enough
time, certain words can become so
decontextualized from their origin story
that they become fully absorbed within
their new context. Like, who would have
thought the names William, Robert,
Richard, Roger, and Hugh, some of the
most British names ever, were actually
introduced to English through Norman
French. If incel terms like maxing,
pled, and mogging, become even more a
part of how we regularly speak, we may
simply lose the origin story of them
altogether. Based on how widespread
their usage is, it seems like this might
already be happening. But what does this
also tell us about who has power right
now? Who gets to create new mainstream
language? Call it the insult conquest of
2026. Actually, ew, please don't call it
[laughter] that. As a sidebar,
colonization is not the only way that
new language gets introduced. This was
just one direction I wanted to explore.
I don't want to make any broad
underresourced claims here, but I just
think it's interesting how, like Cat 10
Burch talked about, there is an agenda
at play when it comes to the billionaire
manosphere class, and I'm sure they're
just all thrilled that we're
incorporating incel speak,
>> men have had a very rough go of it for
just recently, and it ends now.
>> [screaming]
>> This
wench is the most mitching
kiff
rampolian. man I've ever
met.
Trust her not. She is an Elvish
marked.
All right, my beautiful doves. Let's
review what we learned today. Incel
terms like maxing, pills, and mog have
migrated out of incel forums into
mainstream slang, mainly via memes. Many
non- incelss using these terms online
are likely unaware that they have roots
in incel communities. This inundation of
terms feels like a noticeable cultural
shift, at least for me. While online
slang has always originated from
specific subcultures, whether it be from
ballroom culture, AAV, gaming, etc., A
lot of slang in the past few years seems
to be coming from fringe misogynists. I
don't know what this means for us on a
societal level, but it feels creepy when
we pay attention to the origins.
But on their own and decontextualized,
incel terms are funny. The suffix format
of many of them makes them easy to
repurpose into new words, much like the
buzzy non-insel suffixes like ification
core and everyone's favorite. Let's see.
The gloomy tone of insult terms might
also resonate with Gen Z whose
vocabulary is rife with semi-sarcastic
doomspeak memes. It also doesn't have to
reflect anything about our attitudes or
belief systems. It could just be that we
naturally pick up on patterns in
internet language without noticing like
the standardized key smash format and
the evolution of LOL from laugh out loud
to an expression of nonchalants. A lot
of people likely think that using incel
terms robs incelss of their power by
eroding their sense of ingroup identity.
And while it's true that these terms
becoming decontextualized might hurt the
incel cause, as we talked about with Cat
10barge, algorithms could still funnel
people into inceladjacent communities on
social media if they're engaging with
memes containing incel terms. And this
is definitely more dangerous when we're
talking about adolescence and teenagers
who have not gained enough media
literacy or who haven't come into their
sense of self enough to swerve from the
dog whistles. But linguist Adam Alexa
suggested that worrying about the incel
terms leaking into mainstream vocab is
like worrying about the symptoms of a
disease rather than the disease itself.
It might not necessarily be a problem
that maxing and mogging are now
ubiquitous terms as much as it is a
problem that incelss are still a large
online community espousing hateful
rhetoric. If these terms become
completely decontextualized from their
source, chances are incelss will just
come up with new ones. By learning about
the Norman conquest of England and
analyzing words with Anglo-Saxon versus
Latin origins, we can see how colonial
power dynamics have a lasting effect on
language and how the origin story of
certain words can become completely lost
from public knowledge. We definitely
hammered this point home by recreating a
scene from Mean Girls using early modern
English vocabulary, showcasing just how
much language can change over a handful
of centuries. As for where I stand on
this,
I'm personally not too worried about the
mainstream spread of incel terms turning
more people into incelss because I think
all slang is destined to become
decontextualized at some point. In the
same way that we unfortunately don't
often credit black queer people for the
terms their community has contributed to
mainstream slang. I mean, and I guess
like the whole point of this video is
that it's not even just slang, it's just
words in general. I guess my personal
issue with these terms like maxing and
pill is less political and just petty.
Honestly, I think that they're used to
ad nauseium. I feel like all internet
slang terms reach a point of
oversaturation where they're not as
evocative as they used to be. And it
feels like these incel terms are
approaching that. I've definitely seen
something similar happen firsthand with
titles for YouTube videos. For a while,
it felt like every buzzy YouTube video
essay was titled something like the
death of blank or the downfall of blank
or the blankification of blank. And yes,
I was participating in this trend
because it paid off. Those videos I
titled with that template, they
performed better than like any videos I
any other videos I made. Um, I get it.
It's always tempting to adopt popular
internet sling to come off as though
your finger is on the cultural pulse and
hopefully to increase engagement.
Content creation is always hard because
you're trying to catch someone's
attention quickly and cut through all
the noise online. But whenever I find
myself relying on internet slang to
communicate in my day-to-day life, it
sort of feels like a superficial way to
connect with another person. Kate
Lindsay wrote, "Tik Tok speak is often
developed through a single person
talking to an audience. And though for
phrases like, oh, that's not dot dot
dot, do nothing to invite conversation.
They're just reactions meant for people
to thumbs up and move on, which is hard
when you're both facing each other at a
dinner table. Transparently, I don't
think I'll fully stop using internet
slang or talking in memes anytime soon.
I mean, I'm not that pretentious. And I
also think it can be funny and a way to
feel connected with your peers. I
remember someone once posted on Substack
Notes a screenshot of a Bob Dylan
interview. And of course, you know, Bob
Dylan, the way he speaks is so flowery
and esoteric, but someone was like, I
can't believe he's just speaking like
this. And then I think it was Kate who
restacked this post. I'm not sure, but
someone did. And they were like, I
actually started talking kind of like
this when I took a break from social
media. But then I realized it was more
worth it to be connected with everyone
else. So I guess the message is
everything in moderation lest we all end
up sounding like walking talking for you
pages. and stop interacting with brands
in the comment sections, please. Please.
This is the end of the video. Thank you
so much for sticking around, hanging out
with me, listening to me talk about this
subject. Um,
[snorts] I'm like, the video's over. Uh,
and uh, I'll see you next time. I hope
you have a lovely rest of your day.
[music]